Finding Aid for the Philippine Zines Collection LSC.2281
UCLA Library Special Collections
- The Jesus Rocket / I Think My Dog is Pro-Du30 / Danger Man, 2016; de Leon, Marguerite Alcazaren (Box 8, Folder 13)
  From a religious cult bearing 300 rockets to take them to a holier, place, to a shih tzu that seems to have a psychic connection to Rodrigo Duterte, to a romantic relationship tested by a cheap carnival attraction and poor handling of money, this zine-style mini-collection features Marguerite Alcazaren de Leon's latest stories, each with an illustration also by the author.
  Churches; Christmas Fairs; Art; Literature; Religion; Politics; Duterte, Rodrigo
- Jose Rizal, undated; Sta Maria, Apol (Box 4, Folder 23)
  A zine with illustrations dedicated to depicting Jose Rizal, the Philippine's national hero, in different art styles and forms.
  Art; Culture; History; Rizal, Jose
- Just a Bunch of Short Stories, undated; Villa, Noel (Box 4, Folder 24)
  This is a collection of 8 unrelated short stories printed and bound together by a paper fastener. The short stories are marked by the year they are written, ranging from 2009-2012, and follow no particular theme.
  Short Stories; Literature
- Kapitan Bayaran, 2013; Cesario, Joanne; Bacabac, Michelle; 502 Komiks (Box 4, Folder 25)
  Kapitan Bayaran is a Tagalog comic by Joanne Cesario and Michelle Bacabac, and published by 502 Komiks in 2013. It is about a college student, Albert, who wakes up one day and discovers he can read minds and decides to make a business out of it. This comic talks about college students and their concerns with being far away from home, not being able to afford college, student politics, grades, and romantic affairs.
  College Life; Telepathy; Art; Culture; Education; psychology
- Keith Busilak, 2017; Villanueva, Julius (Box 4, Folder 26)
  A one-shot comic about a taxi driver who is experiencing his occupation become obsolete because of Uber and Grab. Despite the hard times, he has faith that President Rodrigo Duterte will uplift the hardworking and the poor.
  War on Drugs; Taxi Driver; Taxi; Uber; economics; Transportation; Politics; Duterte, Rodrigo
- Kindness, 2014; Campos, Rolf (Box 4, Folder 27)
  This item is a one-sided accordion zine (leporello) created by Rolf Campos and dedicated to Don M. Salubayba, a fellow visual artist, and mentor, who passed away. With Don's work characterized by its chaotic dreaminess, and a tendency to sprawl over the surface utilized, the homage becomes apparent through the small details of Rolf's doodles of their adventures together.
  Folded Books; Doodles; Art; Culture; Geography
- The Kiss Of The Demoness, 2016; Pascasio, Gillian (Box 8, Folder 14)
  A comic about a lesbian engineer and demoness who share a contract. The demoness predicts the future for the engineer so she can gamble to earn money, and the engineer pays her back with a kiss.
  LGBT; Queer; Lesbian Fiction; Folklore; Technology
- Komiks Galing Sa Aking Kaluluwa, 2016; Andoyman (Box 4, Folder 28)
  A compilation of quirky, silly comic strips drawn by Andoyman from 2015-2016 that even draw on political commentary with humor. They are comics that are derived from the soul, making the content fairly personal, despite seriousness.
  Body Horror; Politics
- Komikwento, 2015; Dimalanta, Francesca; Serrano, Gabriela (Box 4, Folder 29)
  The Komik About Komiks. This comic is the printed version of a web comic and informative website aimed to promote local, independent komik culture in the Philippines, which is resurfacing again after the initial decline due to censorship during Marcos' martial law. In this comic, two young adults are inspired through a meet-and-greet with a famous komik artist. The artist gives them step-by-step advise on how to start their own komik, and how to navigate the world of publishing.
  Independent Comics; Art; Business; Culture; economics; Education; History; Komikon
- Krus Na Ligaw, 2013; Villena, Ara; Iñigo, Elle; Espino, Giselle (Box 4, Folder 30)
  Krus na Ligaw translates to 'Lost Cross' and is comprised of poems, prose, and visual art compiled by writers from the University of the Philippines, Diliman. With Tagalog poems about the sleep deprived, to stories about simbang gabi, to text art based on single word prompts, Krus na Ligaw provides a wide assortment of stories about journeys, personal or literally.
  Simbang Gabi; Text Art; Art; Literature; Religion
- Kung Alam Ko Lang, 2015; Vee, Brian (Box 4, Folder 31)
  Kung Alam Ko Lang translates to "If Only I Knew." Originally a spoken word poem, Brian Vee wrote this poem for his mother to express his love, gratefulness, and longing for her after she died. Aside from the spoken word poem, a bonus comic, screenshots, and more stories that share his relationship with his mother are included.
  Family; Mourning; Mother; Grief; Literature; Religion
- Kung Pwede Lang Sanang Kainin Ang Zine Na Ito, 2008; UP UGAT (Box 4, Folder 32)
  "If Only This Zine Could Be Eaten" is the English translation of this zine's title, hinting at what the content of the poems and stories inside are going to be about. In the Philippines, most people are no stranger to poverty and the painful hunger it brings upon communities. The stories and poems in this zine show a sliver of some of the devastating economic conditions that pushes people to go as far as beg on the streets and develop addictions to inhaling fumes of an adhesive just to curb their hunger.
  Poverty; Addiction; Hunger; economics; Language; Politics
- Ladies in Teepneys, volume 1, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Lamon, 2015 August; Cosico, Mark Vincent P. (Box 4, Folder 33)
  This printed tour of an exhibition by Mark Vincent in the Sining Makiling Gallery at UP Los Banos is a critique on the culture of consumption in the Philippines. The pieces in Lamon reproduces eating traditions and paints them in a way that reflects the power struggle between consumers and capitalists. The popular figures and icons that are recreated in this exhibit serve to remind viewers the history and politics of the media they usually consume and are currently consuming.
  Capitalism; Food; Pop Culture; Globalization; Resistence; Art; Colonization; Culture; economics; Education; History; Religion; Politics
- Last Animatic Readable Adventures, 2013; Campos, Rolf (Box 4, Folder 34)
  This zine has an assortment of content ranging from photography of supermarkets and graffiti filled walls, collages, and a song lyrics with chords. The most common reccuring image throughout the zine is a small, black, paper fastener puppet.
  Photography; Graffiti; Art
- Last Minute, 2017; Bangalan, Glerren; Lahathala Micro Press (Box 4, Folder 35)
  This is a screenplay about two girls who accidentally meet on a rooftop in Metro Manila with the intention of jumping from it.
  Suicide; Mental Health; Chapbook; Soulmates; Screenplay; Film; Literature; psychology
- Lazy Sunday, 2016; R., Daniel; B., Kimmy; The National Embarrassment (Box 4, Folder 36)
  A zine with illustrations inspired by lyrics to the song "Lazy Sunday," a song that is also by the National Embarrassment. The lyrics are visually incorporated with the collage that is influenced by a surrealist art style.
  collage; Lyrics; Surrealism; Art; Music
- Leave It Blank, undated; Tiu, Pau; Bad Student (Box 4, Folder 37)
  A 2-color risograph zine printed by Bad Student in Manila, Philippines. The pink and blue zine utilizes the white, or empty space for the images.
- Liboter, 2017; Alfasin, Genory Vanz (Box 4, Folder 38)
  Essays, stories, and photostills that were inspired by the experiences and musings that are born after one wanders around. The stories and the poems in this zine are in Cebuano, a Visayan language.
  Travel; Geography; Language; Literature
- License to Quest, undated; Jocson, Luigi (Box 4, Folder 39)
  License to Quest is a one-shot comic by Luigi Jocson or "Lui421." In this world, heroes and adventurers make a living from quests that allow them to embark on adventures outside of the city.
  Parody; Quest; Adventure; Folklore
- Life Is Short Art Is Long, undated; Wombatrai (Box 4, Folder 40)
  A zine with collages and musings the lifespan and immortality of an artist and their art.
  Legacy; Art; Philosophy
- Little Red Book 3, undated; UP UGAT (Box 4, Folder 41)
  A small zine about love published by UP UGAT. In this zine, 17 students contributed their own short stories love as they interpret it.
  Abuse; Romance; Love; Literature
- The Long Weekend, 2011; David, Adam; The Youth and Beauty Brigade (Box 8, Folder 15)
  A story about a strained couple on a long weekend to salvage their declining relationship.
  Travel; Vacation; Comics Novella; Art; Literature
- Lóngos, 2017; Cavite Young Writers Association (Box 4, Folder 42)
  Short Filipino stories and poems that compares the journey of writing to the journey of coming home to Lóngos, a bottleneck area in Cavite. Different pieces in this zine was written by people from the Cavite Young Writers Association (CYWA). These Caviteños often make references to their hometowns, even with the diverse topics of the short stories and poems.
  Cavite (Cavite Province, Philippines); Lóngos (Laguna, Philippines); Literature
- Lore, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Love Bag, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Maggot Brains Underground Comics, 2013 December; Yummy; Bomba! Press (Box 5, Folder 1)
  This is a compilation of comics that consists of subsersive images and messages. The panels feature lots of recreational drug use and graphic content of distorted bodies.
  Sexuality; Drugs; Culture; psychology
- Mahal Kong Maynila, 2017; Estrada, Roma (Box 5, Folder 2)
  A collection of poems and photography that presents Manila as a colorful, bustling city-especially at night.
  Manila (Philippines); City Life; Geography; Literature
- Malaya, 2017; Lauw, Boon (Box 5, Folder 3)
  This is the first few chapters to Boon Lauw's novel that is a work in progress. The story is set during the martial law, and characters who embarked the mountains to be part of the war to end it.
  Makabagong Katipunan ng Pilipinas; War; Martial Law; Guerrilla Warfare; Colonization; Culture; Geography; History; Politics; Literature; Music
- Maliit lang 'yung sa 'yo, itabi mo, magpadaan ka: Adventures in Parataxis, undated; Suarez, Angelo V. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  In this zine, 9 conversations between the author and the taxi driver are transcribed in paratactic form. By putting the exchanges next to each other without indicating who said what, the significance of who is speaking is diminished. This way, the emphasis leans towards what is said in the conversation rather than who said it. These conversations reflect the street smarts of the taxi drivers, as it becomes evident that they hold more information about the cities and streets than the passenger.
  Taxi Driver; Taxi; Travel; Conversation; Parataxis; Anthropology; Language; Culture; Transportation
- Manila Automat Annual Comics Round Up, undated; Agregado, Mica (Box 5, Folder 5)
  This is a compilation of comics by Mica Agregado. The comic panels touch on different subjects-the artist's frustration and self doubt about drawing, a quiet take on the Rapture, a story about mourning, and a panel about a dream.
  Mourning; Semi-autobiographical; Rapture; Art
- Manila Automat Primer, undated; Agregado, Mica (Box 5, Folder 6)
  This introduces us to Mica Agregado as an artist struggling out internal and external hardships when it comes to making comics. Each page shows a different hurdle to overcome as an artist, but the insecurity and peer pressure to conform to other artists is especially highlighted within the pages.
  Semi-autobiographical; Art
- Manimalaman, undated; Ang INK (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Manimalaman is a collaboration zine published by Ang INK (Ilustrador ng Kabataan). The title is derived from the combination of the words man + animal + halaman (plant). Each submission is an artist's original character with the combined traits of a man, animal, and halaman. The submissions also come with a short back story or description of the diverse hybrid creatures.
  Collaboration; Plants; Animals; Art; Culture
- Marcela Chapter 1, undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
- Market Day, 2017; Sinkiangbin (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Printed in color, this zine illustrates a walk through what a common wet market or palengke in the Philippines would look like. Shown are stands for fruit, vegetables, fish, poultry, Filipino desserts like kakanin and an area for miscellaneous items like pots, pans, and baskets.
  Palengke; Markets; Wet Market; Art; Culture; economics
- Marriage, undated; Dela Cruz, Cindy (Box 5, Folder 9)
  A zine filled with poems, flash fiction, and a short story that provides a glimpse into a marriage.
  Marriage; Literature
- Mata, undated; Blue Indie Komiks (Box 5, Folder 10)
  This anthology by artists from BLINK (Blue Indie Komiks) features work with the central theme of the eye, with the genre of the contents ranging from horror to suspense.
  Horror; Eye; Art; Folklore
- Matagal-tagal na rin…, undated; UE Drama Company (Box 5, Folder 11)
  A collection of poems from members of University of the East's Drama Company. The mix of Filipino and English poems in this zine reminisce about the lingering pain of heart break from being left behind by a past lover, or a family member.
  Breaking Up; Death; Literature
- May Pursa Basura, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
- MCHANZO ZINE, undated; Groven (Box 5, Folder 12)
  A fanzine of two Overwatch characters speculated to have a relationship by fans. The zine portrays the two characters outside of their traditional setting and context of the video game.
  Video Games; Overwatch; Technology
- Me | You | Us, undated; Africa, Alyssa (Box 5, Folder 13)
  A photozine with black and white photography of people waiting for their food at restaurants, food, and the people food is shared with. The photos, along with the few words that accompany them, aim to express that that the food we eat, and the people we eat it with, are the experiences that we keep.
  Photography; Food; Art
- Medium, 2016 December; Bascon, Zeus; Basilla, Saturnino (Box 5, Folder 14)
  A selection of drawings, events, musings, observations of the odd and otherworldly. This zine filled with Zeus Bacon 's eerie, and sometimes vulgar, depictions of the otherworldly was printed in Manila, Philippines in 2016.
  Supernatural; Art
- HOW MANY ITEMS? Medyo Gabi And Yet, undated; Busamante, Chubbs A. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  The Taglish poems in this zine depict a drunken walk home between the narrator and the subject of their romantic interest. Drunken ideas of how to salvage the people of the Philippines from poverty are suggested by the poet, all of which the other person denies doing because he believes the revolution is not going to be catalyzed by one person, but rather, the Masa or the People. The poems go on to describe the fray that is Manila, and wonder, how can they still feel love for this person despite being in the midst of collective despair?
  Corruption; Intoxication; Social Justice; Culture; Literature; Politics
- Metallic Carcass, 2017; Padiernos, Alperr (Box 5, Folder 16)
  This photozine contains a series of monochromatic photos of Alperr's daily traverse that highlights the beauty, despite the stress and hardship, of riding the public transit.
  Photography; Monochrome; Light rail transit; Art; Transportation
- Mga Huling Habilin Ni Nikolas, undated; Flores, Catherine A. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  These poems and flash stories are Nikolas' last will and testament. The first part is dedicated to people in his life-father, mother, sister, best friend, and ex-lover. The second part is dedicated to the places that have left a mark on him, and the last part is to his ex-lover.
  Death; Last Will; Literature
- Mga Kwento Sa Loob At Labas Ng Pila, 2017; De Guzman, Dado (Box 5, Folder 18)
  Comic strips to tell stories of people waiting in long, inconvenient lines.
  Lines; Queue; Anthropology
- Midnight - Atmospheric Mindfulness, undated; Garza, Denver (Box 5, Folder 19)
  Original, purple watercolor paintings and designs on watercolor paper. The paintings often obscure the face of the painting's subject.
- MIKI LTD., 2016; Garcellano, Lyra; Flores, W. Don (Box 5, Folder 20)
  Real conversations between Lyra and Don about art and the art scene in the Philippines. Cartoon strips also serve as a commentary on how capitalistic or pretentious said scene can get.
  Art Scene; Art; Business; Culture
- Minsan Gusto Ko Magwala, 2015 April; Aquino, Ardie (Box 5, Folder 21)
  A mini-comic in Filipino about a boy learning to stand up to his bullies.
  Bullying; psychology
- Miss Ria, undated; De Guia, Rayji (Box 5, Folder 22)
  This zine is about a witch doctor, Ria, who made a baby with magic while her husband was away gathering magical herbs.
  Kulam; Family; Witch Doctor; Culture; Folklore; Literature
- Mitolohiya, 2015; Magpies Press (Box 5, Folder 23)
  A multimedia zine with poems, art, and comics in both English and Filipino to debunk the idea that mental health struggles are just myths. Each piece shows vulnerability and perspectives from different people who are going through mental health struggle.
  Erasure Poetry; Mental Health; Depression; Art; Literature
- Mom, Dad, I'm Trash, undated; Asshulz + Friends (Box 5, Folder 24)
  A zine in Taglish explaining what being "trash" means through an introduction, and showing examples of it in illustrations and comic panels. Being "trash" is self-described by Asshulz as the act of making bad decisions, acknowledging it, and then making some more.
  Slang; Anthropology; Language
- The Monthly Soup Zine, 2014; Felipe, Keeshia; Bularan, Paul; Soupzine (Box 8, Folder 16)
  This artzine is a compilation of different local artist's works to showcase the diverse and unique styles of their craft.
  - The Monthly Soup Issue #1, Trinidad, Rasel; Bernabe, Bjan; Nacionales, Francesca (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - The Monthly Soup Issue #2, Mr. Yeti; Clemente, Calorozy; Santos, Dana (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Motivation, 2017; CreativeK (Box 5, Folder 25)
  A comic on how to stay motivated while creating comics. The advise spans from how to handle time management, to how to digest harsh, constructive criticism.
  comics; Constructive Criticism; Education
- Mound of Glutton, 2017; Fabonan, Miles; Studio Soup Zine (Box 5, Folder 26)
  A compilation of acrylic paintings that mostly depicts excessively greedy eaters through paintings that emphasize the mouth, teeth, and monsters.
  Traditional Art; Gluttony; Art
- Moxie, undated (Box 10, Folder 47)
- Mula Sa Mualan, 2013 December; Mendoza, Pamela; Gonzales, Paulyne; Cledera, Shaunnah Ysabel; Magpies Press (Box 5, Folder 27)
  This zine is a compilation of poems by students at the University of the Philippines, Los Baños. The title of the poem is an indicator of the content's focus on eating disorders. 'Mula Sa Mualan' translates to "From a Full Mouth" and dig deep into the feelings of those recovering or still struggling with eating disorders.
  Mental Health; Eating Disorders; Recovery; Health; Literature; psychology
- Mula sa Silong, 2016; De La Cruz, Christa I.; Librong LIRA (Box 5, Folder 28)
  A collection of Filipino poems that do not share an overarching theme, but are part of her broader poetry project. The poems have won the Palanca Memorial Awards for Literature in the past.
- Multiplex-Paranoia[s]; Depressive Glomera, undated; Shonenbat Collective (Box 5, Folder 29)
  Through code poetry, this zine provides a criticism on the high demands of academics that has contributed to the development of paranoia and depression amongst students. Several lesson plans are laid out ironically, and made to seem absurd from the work load and complication of combining literature and coding.
  Depression; Mental Health; Paranoia; Code Poetry; Education; Literature; Technology
- multivitamin zine, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  A colorful zine about food. It includes illustrations and photographs of food, as well as a few words on mannerisms around food.
  Food; Food Pyramid; Health
- Munting Alagads, 2017; Batocabe, Abbey (Box 5, Folder 31)
  A zine about "small slaves" who wonder about their existence and purpose. The munting alagad are all identical, and are all drawn in the same sketchy art style. The munting alagad all speak in Taglish
  Taglish; Anthropology
- My Biggest Fear, undated; Chuatico, Danielle (Box 5, Folder 32)
  A one-shot comic dedicated to the creator's anniversary with her boyfriend.
  Relationship; College Life; Anniversary; Anthropology
- My Biggest Fear, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
- My Children, 2017; Patenio, Abelink; SPIT Zines (Box 5, Folder 33)
  A collection of short stories that have gore, paranormal, and psychological elements for a horror-themed zine. Aside from the stories, this zine has bizarre and dream-like illustrations for each story.
  Horror; Gore; Literature; psychology
- The Mybuhigh Daze, 2013; Balita, Nino (Box 8, Folder 17)
  This zine is a photo diary of the artist from the past few years, years which were mostly devoted to graffiti art. The photos feature portraits of people, nature and skylines, artists making graffiti, but mostly graffiti covered anything-from walls, to small boats, and vans.
  Graffiti; Art; Culture
- Nagkomiks, Nagkokomiks, Magkokomiks, 2016; Andoyman (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Comic panels about the common trials and tribulations of aspiring comic artists.
  Comic Conventions; Art; Business; Komikon
- nihil vers: ode to deCo - art - app, 2014 July 15; Acuña, Tilde (Box 6, Folder 2)
  This zine is a combination of text and illustrations. The text expresses the discontentment and dissent against the repression and violation of human rights.
  Censorship; Politics; Repression; Culture; Education
- No Labels, undated; Gomez, Jasper (Box 6, Folder 3)
  This zine is about defying stereotypes and has illustrations and quotes made by various artists, writers and figures to supplement the message.
  Stereotypes; Anthropology; Art; Race
- No Shut-Eye, 2017 February; Uy, Kim; Pelikomiks Studios (Box 6, Folder 4)
  This is an anthology of true horror stories based on interviews over beer and coffee with a policeman, a doctor, and an old, retired doctor. This anthology of Filipino horror stories was published in Manila, Philippines.
  Horror Stories; Interview; Literature; psychology
- No. 24, 2017; Ayi, Fabo; Gerrie, Mama (Box 6, Folder 5)
  This family zine matches the topic of food and meals with colorful and vibrant Illustrations. It plays with the idea of things that are hard to swallow, provides recipes for tofu sandwiches and chickenpeas curry, includes a short story about the 2017 avian flu breakout in Central Luzon.
  Family; Recipes; Avian Flu; Art
- The Nomads Quarterly, 2013 March; Bomba! Press (Box 8, Folder 18)
  The Nomads Quarterly is a literary and arts magazine that includes fictions, essays/reviews, poetry, art pieces, and interviews. The submissions in the first issue included submissions in English, Tagalog, and Cebuano, including an interview with Butch Bandillo, who is considered to be the "father of modern Cebuano poetry." The magazine welcomes submissions, as well as financial contributions to sustain the publication.
  Siargao (Philippines); Bisayan; Cebuano; Art; Language; Literature
- Obosen, 2017; Pineda, Acie (Box 6, Folder 6)
  A short zine with illustrations of various types of paper, from newspaper, advertisements, sticky notes, mail, and others. It also includes news and ideas about the Duterte administration.
  War on Drugs; Feminism; Tokhang; History; psychology; Politics; Duterte, Rodrigo
- Odds And Ends, 2017; Pinpin, Vaughn (Box 6, Folder 7)
  A short collection of comics and drawings by Vaughn Pinpin that follow the vanities and misfortunes of his life.
  Freelance; Culture; Art